<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Frameworks | Jaydson Gomes]]></title>
  <link href="http://jaydson.org/blog/categories/frameworks/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jaydson.org/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-02T02:46:49-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://jaydson.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jaydson Gomes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mibbu - Framework Javascript para Games]]></title>
    <link href="http://jaydson.org/mibbu-framework-javascript-para-games/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-23T02:00:30-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://jaydson.org/mibbu-framework-javascript-para-games</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had the pleasure of personally meeting <a href="http://michalbe.blogspot.com/">Michal Budzynski </a> at <a href="http://jaydson.org/brazil-js-2011-epicwin">BrazilJS</a>.<br/>
Among many excellent lectures, Michal's really opened the minds of many people.<br/>
Games developed in Javascript have been around for a long time, as its showed Michal, but now increasingly it becomes a reality.</p>

<p>Today I speak of a framework created by Michal, the <a href="http://mibbu.eu/"><strong>Mibbu</strong></a>.<br/>
Mibbu provides everything you need to create a game in Javascript quickly less than 2.5KB of code.<br/>
One of the features that caught my attention in Mibbu was the option to create Games both using Canvas or DOM.<br/>
You can choose which type of rendering with just one function call, so your game can run in browsers that support Canvas, or those that do not support.<br/>
Since version 0.2(that came out today 23/05/2011 <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/michalbe/status/72435732635070464">http://twitter.com/#!/michalbe/status/72435732635070464</a>)  Mibbu supports CSS3 animations O/</p>

<p><strong>Mibbu </strong><strong>Features</strong><strong>:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Rendering game using both - Canvas or DOM</li>
<li>Animation of the sprites (using Canvas, DOM or CSS Animation in Webkit)</li>
<li>Collisions detection with collision zones</li>
<li>Simple background manager</li>
<li>Callbacks after given number of frames</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Exemple:<br/>
</strong>Open Odyssey - Open-source Javascript game created with Mibbu Framework</p>

<p><strong>Z</strong> Shoot and move with arrows</p>

<p>Curiosity:<br/>
Both Mibbu and Open Odyssey was created by Michal in 5 daysa to <a href="https://gaming.mozillalabs.com/">Mozilla GameOn Competition</a>.</p>

<p>Both projects are obviously on GitHub:<br/>
Mibbu: <a href="https://github.com/michalbe/mibbu/">https://github.com/michalbe/mibbu/</a><br/>
Open Odyssey: <a href="https://github.com/michalbe/open-odyssey">https://github.com/michalbe/open-odyssey</a></p>

<p>Fork and start now to develop your Javascript games!</p>

<h1>Michal Budzynski</h1>

<p>Tive o prazer de conhecer pessoalmente o <a href="http://michalbe.blogspot.com/">Michal Budzynski </a>no <a href="http://jaydson.org/brazil-js-2011-epicwin">BrazilJS</a>.<br/>
Dentre tantas excelentes palestras, a do Michal realmente abriu a mente de muitas pessoas.<br/>
Jogos desenvolvidos em Javascript já existem há um bom tempo, como o próprio Michal mostrou, mas agora cada vez mais isso se torna uma realidade.</p>

<p>Hoje venho falar de um Framework criado pelo Michal, o <a href="http://mibbu.eu/"><strong>Mibbu</strong></a>.<br/>
O Mibbu fornece tudo que precisamos para criar um jogo em Javascript de maneira rápida, e isso com menos de 2.5KB de código .<br/>
Uma das <em>features</em> que me chamou a atençao no Mibbu, foi a possibildade de criar Games tanto utilizando Canvas ou DOM .<br/>
É possível escolher qual o tipo de reenderização com apenas uma chamada de função, desta maneira o seu jogo pode rodar tanto em navegadores que suportam Canvas, ou naqueles que não suportam .<br/>
Desde a versão 0.2(que saiu hoje, 23/05/2011 http://twitter.com/#!/michalbe/status/72435732635070464) o Mibbu também suporta animações em CSS3 O/</p>

<p><strong>Features do Mibbu:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Reenderização usando Canvas ou DOM</li>
<li>Animação de Sprites (usando Canvas, DOM ou CSS3)</li>
<li>Detecção de Colisão, com definição de zonas de colisão</li>
<li>Gerenciamento de plano de fundo</li>
<li>Funções callback depois de um certo número de frames</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Exemplo:<br/>
</strong>Open Odyssey - Jogo open-source Javascript criado utilizando o Mibbu Framework</p>

<p><strong>Z</strong> Atira e as setas movem o boneco</p>

<p>Curiosidade:<br/>
Tanto o Mibbu quanto o Open Odyssey foram criados pelo Michal em 5 dias para a <a href="https://gaming.mozillalabs.com/">Mozilla GameOn Competition</a>.</p>

<p>Ambos projetos obviamente estão no GitHub:<br/>
Mibbu: <a href="https://github.com/michalbe/mibbu/">https://github.com/michalbe/mibbu/</a><br/>
Open Odyssey: <a href="https://github.com/michalbe/open-odyssey">https://github.com/michalbe/open-odyssey</a></p>

<p>Faça um fork, e comece agora a desenvolver seus jogos em Javascript!</p>

<h1>Michal Budzynski</h1>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
